Contact

txnikiel1@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/anita-nikiel-98b7148 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Nursing ACLS BLS

Anita Nikiel

Registered Nurse - THPFM ER

Dallas/Fort Worth Area

Summary

I am currently looking for a position that I can continue to advance my medical experience. I have been in the medical field for 39 years, have worked everywhere from Emergency rooms, to pediatrics, telemetry, occupational nursing, free standing ER/Urgent Care as an RN and as pre-hospital ALS care as a Paramedic.

CPR

ACLS

TNCC

PALS

CEN 2010-2014

Experience

Texas Health Presbyterian Hospital Flower Mound Emergency Room April 2010 - Present (10 years 4 months)

One of the nighttime charge nurses in the emergency department. Currently responsible for patient care, including triage, assessment, treatment, and proper administration of medications. As Charge I am responsible for shift management and patient flow. I help with the coordination of care of patient between the different departments within the hospital. I precept new staff and am a credentialed EPIC trainer for our department.

As an ER nurse I am able to anticipate and respond to patient needs, and changing medical conditions. I assess and stabilize patients. I am able to triage and prioritize patients so that they get the appropriate care and in a timely manner. I also work well with the physicians and other team members.

Coordination of discharge phone calls

Credentialed ED trainer EPIC

Med host

CPSI

2014 representative for THFM ER for the THR Rose Award.

Accountable Healthcare Staffing

Travel RN

April 2018 - Present (2 years 4 months)

EHR consultant to help facilitate the conversion to EPIC within the Emergency dept.

Plummer Project - ED. (Mayo Big Bang)

ERCA

RN

February 2015 - January 2017 (2 years)

Plano Texas

As an RN with ERCA I am responsible for the care of patients; infant to elderly. I am responsible for the triage, assessment, treatment of patients, following MD orders. I am fluent in Docutap charting system. As with many free-standing ERs and Urgent Care places, I am responsible for stocking, care, treatment including IV, medications, respiratory treatment and management, and transfers.

Medix™

RN

March 2014 - January 2016 (1 year 11 months)

travel

EHR consultant to help with implementation of Medhost in ERs

Medical Center of Lewisville

1 year 8 months

RN

September 2008 - March 2010 (1 year 7 months)

ER nurse in the Flower Mound Emergency Center.

T System

Registered Nurse

August 2008 - March 2010 (1 year 8 months)

Lewisville TX

Registered Nurse CDU and Emergency Room

Within the Clinical Decision Unit my job entailed the delivery of care and continuation of care as ordered by the Emergency Room physician for the rule of Cardiac Events and other medical care. Within the ER I was responsible for the initial care and treatment of patients that came through the ER for their care. Being an Emergency Nurse requires a well rounded nurse that can triage and care for a myriad of patients that come to Emergency rooms for the acute care and primary care of medical problems. IV, medication, assessment and splinting are just a few of the skills required of an Emergency Room nurse. Good bedside manner is a staple to ER care.

Was involved in
Peer Council
Computer charting system
T system
Meditech

Healix Infusion
Nurse Coordinator
January 2003 - September 2007 (4 years 9 months)

Contract nurse for local facilities for infusion of Remicade, IVIG, IV Iron, and IV Antibiotics. Responsible for the day to day running of the infusion office. Safe medication infusion, IVs, charting, follow up care and calls to patient physicians. Initially had a Pharmacist working in infusion center, but later was responsible for the mixing and administration of medication. Responsible for patient teaching of medications including Hepaitis C medications. During the winter of 2006-2007 ran the Synagis program for a local MD's office through Healix.

Brown Mackie College instructor
August 2005 - June 2006 (11 months)
Clinical instructor in the Medical Assistant program.

Moirristown Memorial Hosp Paramedic. NJ cert number 0730 1983 - 1998 (15 years)

Medic units worked in that time period- MIC11, Medic1, medic 2, ALS 16, MIC21, 31, 51,71.

Education

County College of Morris AS, Nursing · (1995 - 1998)